<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>An act for sale of the goods and personal estate of the late King, Queen &amp; Prince. Vicesimo sexto Junii, 1649. Ordered by the Commons assembled in Parliament, that this Act be forthwith printed and published. Hen: Scobell, Cleric. Parliament'.</title>
            <title>Laws, etc.</title>
            <author>England and Wales.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1649</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 29 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 9 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2012-10">2012-10 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A74085</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Thomason E1060_44</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R10874</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99858896</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99858896</idno>
            <idno type="VID">169034</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A74085)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 169034)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Thomason Tracts ; 157:E1060[44])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>An act for sale of the goods and personal estate of the late King, Queen &amp; Prince. Vicesimo sexto Junii, 1649. Ordered by the Commons assembled in Parliament, that this Act be forthwith printed and published. Hen: Scobell, Cleric. Parliament'.</title>
                  <title>Laws, etc.</title>
                  <author>England and Wales.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>p. [2], 331-346, [1] [i.e. 17 ] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>printed for Edward Husband, printer to the Parliament of England, and are to be sold at his shop in Fleetstreet, at the sign of the Golden-Dragon, near the Inner-Temple,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1649.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Signatures: 3M-3N⁴ 3O² . Also issued as part of a through-paged set with a table for the entire set added.</note>
                  <note>The last leaf is blank.</note>
                  <note>On 3M2: last word of first line of text: "and"; first word of line below initial: "in"; last word of last full line: "every".</note>
                  <note>Ornament on t.p.; initial letter; text in black letter</note>
                  <note>Reproductions of the originals in the British Library (Thomason Tracts) and the Huntington Library (Early English books).</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Charles --  I, --  King of England, 1600-1649 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Henrietta Maria, --  Queen, consort of Charles I, King of England, 1609-1669 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Charles --  II, --  King of England, 1630-1685 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  Civil War, 1642-1649 --  Confiscations and contributions --  Law and legislation --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  Commonwealth and Protectorate, 1649-1660 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-09</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-09</date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:169034:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>AN ACT For Sale of the Goods and Perſonal Eſtate Of the late King, Queen &amp; Prince.</p>
            <figure>
               <figDesc>seal of the Commonwealth, composed of two juxtaposed blazons, one bearing the image of St. George's cross, the other of an Irish harp</figDesc>
            </figure>
            <p>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="license">
                        <opener>
                           <dateline>
                              <date>Viceſimo ſexto Junii, 1649.</date>
                           </dateline>
                        </opener>
                        <p>ORdered by the Commons aſſembled in Parliament, That this Act be forthwith printed and publiſhed.</p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>Hen: Scobell, Cleric. Parliament'.</signed>
                        </closer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>London,</hi> Printed for <hi>Edward Huſband,</hi> Printer to the Parliament of <hi>England,</hi> and are to be ſold at his Shop in Fleetſtreet, at the Sign of the Golden-Dragon, near the Inner-Temple, 1649.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="332" facs="tcp:169034:2"/>
            <gap reason="missing" extent="1+ pages">
               <desc>〈1… pages missing〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <p>or any of them, ſhall be inventoried and appriſed, and ſhall alſo be ſold, except ſuch parcels there, of as ſhall be found neceſſary to be reſerved for the uſes of State; Be it therefore Enacted, and it is Enacted by this preſent Parliament, and by the authority of the ſame, That <hi>John Hum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phreys</hi> and <hi>George Withers</hi> of <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> Eſqs; <hi>An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thony Mildmay, Ralph Grafton</hi> of <hi>Cornhil, Michael Lampier, John Belchamp, Philip Cartwright</hi> of the Iſle of <hi>Jerſey,</hi> Sent, <hi>Henry Creech, John Foach, Da<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vid Powel,</hi> and <hi>Edward Winſlow,</hi> Gentlemen, and Citizens of <hi>London,</hi> ſhall be, and are hereby con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtituted and appointed Truſtees for the enqui<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring out, inventorying, apprizing and ſecuring of the ſaid Goods and Perſonal Eſtate; and they, or any four or more of them, ſhall be, and are hereby authorized, to repair to any and every houſe or place whatſoever, where any of the ſaid goods, or any part of the ſaid Perſonal Eſtate doth lie, and to make or cauſe to be made, a true and perfect Inventory or Inventories thereof, and of every part and parcel thereof, which they ſhall or may any way finde out or diſcover, and to make a juſt and equal apprizement of the ſame, and of every part and parcel thereof, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the true value thereof, as they in their judgements and conſciences ſhall think the ſame may reaſonably and probably be ſold for; expreſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing in the ſaid Inventory or Inventories, the ſeveral ſums or values at which the ſeveral par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cels ſhall be apprized as aforeſaid, and to ſecure, or cauſe to be ſecured, the ſaid goods, and every part and parcel thereof, at ſuch place or places, and in the hands and cuſtody of ſuch perſon or perſons as they ſhall finde moſt fit and conveni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ent, to prevent any ſpoil or imbezlement thereof; of which Inventory or Inventories, with the ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral
<pb n="333" facs="tcp:169034:2"/> Apprizements of the premiſes, the ſaid Truſtees, or any four or more of them, ſhall make three Duplicates, certified under their hands and Seals, and expreſsing the ſeveral places where, and the perſons in whoſe Cuſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy the premiſes or any part thereof reſpectively are ſecured as aforeſaid; and keeping the Origi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nals in the hands of ſuch Clerk: Regiſter as they ſhall think fit to imploy, ſhall within fourteen days after any ſuch apprizements made, return and ſend one of the ſaid Duplicates to the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cel of State, which ſhall be kept by the Secre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tary thereof; and the other to the other Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſsioners hereafter named to be Contractors for ſale of the ſaid Goods, or to the Clerk-Regi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter whom the ſaid Contractors ſhall imploy for that purpoſe, which ſhall by him be Regiſtred and ſafe kept; and the third to the Treaſurers hereafter mentioned, for the Receipt of the mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neys to be made by ſale of the premiſes, which ſhall by them be Regiſtered and ſafe kept. And for the more effectual proſecution of this Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice, and better diſcovery of any concealment or imbezlement of the premiſes, or any part there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of, Be it further Enacted, That the ſaid Tru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtees, or any two or more of them, ſhall be and are hereby authorized to adminiſter an Oath unto, and to examine upon Oath every ſuch per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon or perſons as they ſhall finde able to inform them, concerning any other perſon or perſons chargeable with, or accountable for the premiſes or any part thereof: And that the ſaid Truſtees, or any four or more of them, ſhall be and are hereby authorized, by warrant under their hands and Seals, to ſummon and call before them all and every ſuch perſon and perſons, and the Executors or Adminiſtrators of any ſuch
<pb n="334" facs="tcp:169034:3"/> perſon or perſons deceaſed, in whoſe hands, Charge or Cuſtody they ſhall finde, or be inform<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed upon Dath that any of the ſaid goods or pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſes, or any Books of Accompts or Writing concerning the ſame, now are or have been, or were at any time ſince the beginning of the late King <hi>Charls</hi> his Raign, or who ſhall or may be able to inform them concerning the premiſes, or any part thereof; and to require every ſuch perſon or perſons to bring before them all ſuch Books of Accompts, &amp; other Writing as he or they have in their cuſtody or power, or may lawfully come by concerning the premiſes or any part thereof; &amp; in caſe of any ſuch perſons refuſal or neglect of obedience unto ſuch firſt Warrant, then by other Warrant under their hands and Seals, to ſend for ſuch perſon or perſons in ſafe cuſtody (unleſs the perſon be a Member of Parliament or of the Councel of State, in which caſe the Parliament or Councel of State reſpectively, is firſt to be acquainted therewith, to the end ſuch perſon may be ordered and made to appear, and do ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the ſuch firſt Warrant as aforeſaid) and upon the appearance of any ſuch perſon or perſons as aforeſaid in ſafe cuſtody, or otherwiſe, the ſaid Truſtees, or any four or more of them, are hereby authorized to examine, and to require an accompt of every or any ſuch perſon or per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons concerning the diſpoſal of the premiſes, or any part thereof, either upon Oath (Which they are hereby authorized to adminiſter) or elſe with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out Oath, as they ſhall ſee cauſe; and in caſe any ſuch perſon or perſons ſhall refuſe to anſwer, or give ſuch accompt, being thereunto required, then by Warrant under their hands and Seals to commit ſuch Offendor or Offendors to Priſon or ſafe cuſtody, and him or them ſo to detain until
<pb n="335" facs="tcp:169034:3"/> he or they ſhall anſwer and give ſuch accompt as aforeſaid; and in caſe any ſuch perſon or perſons upon his or their own examinations, or other ſufficient evidence upon Oath, ſhall be found to have any of the ſaid Goods or perſonal Eſtate in his or their hands, cuſtody or power, and ſhall detain, or ſhall conceal, and refuſe or neglect to produce and deliver the ſame to ſuch perſon or perſons as the ſaid Truſtees, or any four or more of them ſhall order and appoint, or elſe to have imbezled, purloyned or made away any part or parcel of the premiſes, and ſhall refuſe or neg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lect to bring or pay in to the Treaſury hereafter in this Act appointed, the full value thereof in money, as upon like evidence as aforſaid the ſame ſhall be found to have been worth, when laſt known to have been in his or their hands or cuſtody, and as ſhall thereupon be A warded and Ordered by the ſaid Truſtees (which they, or any four or more of them are hereby authorized and inabled in ſuch caſe to Award and Order) then the ſaid Truſtees, or any four or more of them, are hereby authorized and required to certifie the name and caſe of every ſuch Offendor, with the ful value of the goods by him detained, concealed, imbezled, purioyned, or made away as aforeſaid, unto the Barons of the Exchequer, who there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon are to take order for the effectual levying of the full value ſo certified of the ſaid Goods ſo detained, concealed, imbezled, purloyned, or made away as aforeſaid, upon the Eſtate Real and Perſonal of every ſuch Offendor reſpective<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly; which moneys ſo to be levied, the ſaid Ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rons of the Exchequer are to cauſe to be im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mediately paid over into the hands of the Trea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſurers hereafter mentioned for the uſes in this Act appointed; and in caſe upon ſuch Inquiry,
<pb n="336" facs="tcp:169034:4"/> Information, Examination, or other proceed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing as aforeſaid, any part or parcel of the ſaid goods or premiſes, be found out, produced and recovered in kinde by the ſaid Truſtees, they are then from time to time to proceed therewith, to the inventorying, appriſing and ſecuring the ſame, and returning ſuch Duplicates thereup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on as is afore directed: And in caſe they finde any part or parcel of the premiſes do lie at ſuch place and diſtance, as that they cannot conve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niently go to apprize the ſame where it lies, they may, and are hereby authorized to take order for the true inventorying of the ſame, and for the removing thereof to ſuch other place as they ſhall finde convenient, by the hands of ſuch per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon or perſons as they ſhall think fit to employ therein, in order to their more convenient appri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing and diſpoſing of the ſame, as is afore di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rected. And it is further Enacted, That the ſaid Councel of State, upon the return of any ſuch Duplicate unto them, as is afore directed, from the ſaid Truſtees, ſhall within fourteen days after ſuch return, make choice of ſuch par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticulars of the premiſes therein contained, as they ſhall think fit, to be reſerved for the uſes of State, not exceeding the value of Ten thouſand pounds, and ſend an extract and accompt there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of to the Contractors here after named (who are thereupon to forbear any ſale of ſuch particu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lars, until further Order from the Parliament: And the ſaid Councel of State are with all convenient ſpeed, to certifie or make report to the Parliament, of ſuch particulars as they have ſo made choice of, to be reſerved as aforeſaid, to receive the approbation, or diſapprobation of the Parliament thereupon: And ſuch of the ſaid particulars as the Parliament ſhall thereupon
<pb n="337" facs="tcp:169034:4"/> approve, to be reſerved, ſhall (upon a Warrant from the ſaid Councel) be delivered by the ſaid Truſtees, or their Agents in whoſe Cuſtody the ſame are ſecured as aforeſaid, unto ſuch perſon or perſons as the ſaid councel ſhall authorize and appoint to receive the ſame, to be reſerved for the uſes of the State; and ſuch of the ſaid particu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lars ſo made choice of, as the Parliament ſhall not approve to be reſerved, the ſaid Councel ſhall within ſeven days after ſuch diſapprobation cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tifie to the ſaid Contractors hereafter named, who may and are thereupon to proceed unto the ſale thereof, as is hereafter directed; And the ſaid Truſtees, or any four or more of them, ſhall be and are hereby authorized to make choice of, and appoint a Clerk-Regiſter, and ſuch other Agents or Officers as they ſhall think fit and finde needful, for the better diſcharge of the Truſt, and diſpatch of the Service hereby com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted to them as aforeſaid, and for their own and their Agents and Officers pains and charges therein, ſhall have ſeven pence in the pound allowed them out of all ſuch moneys as ſhall be made by ſale of the ſaid goods and premi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes, and out of the moneys to be received, raiſed or levied for, and as the value of any part or parcel of the premiſes which they ſhall finde or diſcover to be concealed, detained, imbezled, pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>loyned or made away as aforeſaid, which allow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance of ſeven pence <hi>per</hi> pound, ſhall be paid by the Treaſurers here after mentioned, unto the ſaid Truſtees, or to ſuch perſon or perſons as they or any five or more of them ſhall from time to time appoint to receive the ſame for their uſe, by war<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant under their hands and Seals to the ſaid Treaſurers directed; out of which allowance of ſeven pence <hi>per</hi> pound, they are to ſatisfie all and
<pb n="338" facs="tcp:169034:5"/> every the Agents and Officers by them to be employed in this ſervice, and to defray all other charges of the ſame (except for ſuch Meſſengers or Officers as they ſhall employ, for the bring<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing or keeping of any Offenders in ſafe cuſtody as aforeſaid; who for their pains and ſervice therein, are to have and take from every ſuch Offender, ſuch fees as Meſſengers employed under the Sergeant at Arms attending the Parliament uſually do, and lawfully may receive and take for Delinquents fetched or kept by them in ſafe cuſtody, by Order of Parliament reſpectively. And it is further Enacted by the authority aforeſaid, That <hi>Daniel Norman</hi> of the Iſle of <hi>Jerſey,</hi> Merchant, <hi>John Hales</hi> of <hi>London</hi> Merchant, <hi>Clement Kinnerſley, John Price, Henry Parre,</hi> and <hi>William Allen,</hi> Gentlemen and Citizens of <hi>London,</hi> ſhall be, and are hereby conſtituted and appointed Commiſſioners and Contractors for the ſale of all and every the ſaid goods and premiſes, whereof ſuch Duplicates of the inven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>torying and apprizements thereof ſhall be certi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fied and returned to them from the ſaid Truſtees as aforeſaid, except ſuch parcels or particulars thereof as ſhall be made choice of &amp; approved as aforeſaid to be reſerved for the uſes of the State: And the ſaid Contractors, or any three or more of them, are hereby entruſted and authorized to ſell all and ſingular the premiſes (except before ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cepted) according to their beſt skill and judge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, to the beſt advantage for the Common<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wealth, and for the uſes hereafter expreſſed; and for that purpoſe, cauſing publique notice to be given by the ſpace of one week beforehand or more, of the time and place when and where they intend to begin to ſet to ſale any part or parcel of the premiſes, and of the ſeveral parti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>culars
<pb n="339" facs="tcp:169034:5"/> then and there to be ſold, they are accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ingly to proceed to the ſale thereof; and are here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by authorized to treat with any ſuch perſon or perſons who ſhall appear willing to buy, and to Contract with him or them for every or any of the ſaid particulars ſo ſet to ſale, at the utmoſt price they can obtain for the ſame, ſo as it fall not ſhort of the apprizement made as aforeſaid, un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſs (upon further conſideration thereof) the ſaid Truſtees, or four or more of them, ſhall finde cauſe, and agree to alter the ſame unto a lower rate; and ſhall by writing under their hands and Seals certifie ſuch alteration to the ſaid Contractors, in which caſe the ſaid Contra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctors may ſell any ſuch particular or particulars at or above the rate or rates unto which the ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prizement ſhall be ſo altered reſpectively; and in ſuch caſe the ſaid Truſtees are alſo in like maner to certifie the alteration or alterations ſo made, both unto the Councel of State, and to the Trea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſurers hereafter mentioned; and of all and eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry the particulars ſold and contracted for as aforeſaid, and of the buyers names and places of abode, and the prices agreed upon reſpective<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly; and the ſaid Contractors are immediately up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the Contract to cauſe an Entry to be made in a Book, to be kept by their Clerk-Regiſter for that purpoſe, and to ſuch Entry the buyers to ſubſcribe their names reſpectively, which Entry and Subſcription ſhall make the bargain obli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ging on both parts; and for further aſſurance thereof to the buyers (if it be by them inſiſted on) the ſaid Contractors, or any three or more of them, are to give a Note under their Hands and Seals unto the ſeveral buyers reſpectively, ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſſing the particulars by them bought, and the prices, and upon and according to the Entries
<pb n="340" facs="tcp:169034:6"/> made as aforeſaid, the ſaid Contractors, or any three or more of them, ſhall by writing under their Hands and Seals, from time to time cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tifie unto the ſaid Truſtees, and to the Treaſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rers hereafter mentioned ſeverally, an account of the particulars ſold, with the buyers names and prices, and day of ſale reſpectively; and be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore delivery of any the particulars ſold unto the reſpective buyers, the ſaid Contractors are to cauſe the full price or prices agreed upon for the ſame, to be paid into the hands of the Treaſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rers hereafter mentioned in this Act, unleſs they ſhall finde cauſe to give day for part thereof; in which caſe it is left to them ſo to do, ſo as that part exceed not the moyety of the full price, and ſo as the day given exceed not two moneths, and that ſufficient ſecurity be taken by them for the ſum forborn, and upon payment of the full price agreed upon, or of one moyety or more thereof, and ſuch ſecurity taken as aforeſaid for the re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mainder, the payment being certified by the Treaſurers, and the ſecurity by three or more of the Contractors unto the ſaid Truſtees, they the ſaid Truſtees, or three or more of them, ſhall give out their Order or Warrant, directed to the perſon or perſons in whoſe hands ſuch particu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lars were ſecured by them as aforeſaid, for the delivery of ſuch particulars unto the buyer or buyers reſpectively, or to his or their aſſigns; and ſhall alſo make and deliver unto every ſuch buyer or buyers in writing under their hands and Seals, an Aſſignment of the ſaid particulars re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpectively, in the nature of a Bill of Sale, where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by the propriety of the particulars ſo aſſigned, ſhall be fully beſted in ſuch buyer and buyers reſpectively, and in his or their Aſſigns, by vertue of this Act; And in caſe any perſon or
<pb n="341" facs="tcp:169034:6"/> perſons, who ſhall have bargained with the ſaid Contractors as aforeſaid for any of the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſes, ſhall not within the ſpace of one moneth after the contract made and entred as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, effectually proſecute his or their bargain, by paying the ful price, or one moyety thereof or more, and giving ſuch Security for the remainder, as ſhall be inſiſted on by the ſaid Contractors, ſo as the default lie on the part of ſuch buyer or buyers, then every ſuch buyer for ſuch default, ſhall incur the penalty and forfeiture of one fourth part of the ſum of the price agreed on; which upon cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tificate of ſuch default, with the ſum of the pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nalty, from three or more of the ſaid Contra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctors, under their hands and Seals, unto the Barons of the Exchequer, the ſaid Barons ſhall take order for the levying of the ſame to the uſe of the Commonwealth, out of the Eſtate Real and Perſonal of ſuch defaulter or defaul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters reſpectively, and every ſuch defaulter ſhall alſo forfeit and loſe the benefit of his ſaid bar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gain, and in ſuch caſe after the ſpace of ſeven days from the expiration of the ſaid moneths ſpace next enſuing, the Contract; and ſuch de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fault continuing, then the ſaid Contractors, or any three or more of them, may and ſhall pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceed to a new ſale of all and every ſuch particu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lars (concerning which ſuch default is made) unto any other perſon or perſons, as if no ſale thereof had before been made: But where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>as divers of the ſaid goods and premiſes are of ſuch nature, as that though by reaſon of their Rarity or Antiquity, they may yield very great prices in foraign parts, where ſuch things are much valued, yet for particular mens uſe in <hi>England,</hi> they would be accounted little worth, and ſo yield no conſiderable price, if they
<pb n="342" facs="tcp:169034:7"/> ſhould be forthwith ſold here, according to the foregoing directions: It is therefore further Enacted and Provided, That for ſuch particu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lars of the premiſes as the ſaid Contractors ſhall finde to be of that nature, they or any three or more of them may treat and agree with any Merchant Adventurer or Forreign Merchant, about tranſporting ſuch of the ſaid goods into any Forreign parts where they may be ſold at the beſt rates, and either by immediate ſale there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of to ſuch Merchants, to be by them tranſport<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed and ſold as their own (in which caſe the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tractors may give ſuch day or days for payment, as they ſhall finde needful and convenient, for the better improvement of the price) or elſe by hiring the Tranſportation of ſuch things into Forreign parts where they may beſt ſell, &amp; there procuring them to be ſold for this State, the ſaid Contractors are left to take the beſt courſe they can, according to their beſt skil &amp; judgements, to ſell ſuch things to the utmoſt advantage of the <hi>Commonwealth,</hi> although it be in a way differing from that which is before in general directed for other parts of the premiſes, Any thing in this Act contained to the contrary notwithſtanding. Provided always, That no ſuch particulars of the premiſes be ſold to Merchants here, or tranſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ported into other parts, to be ſold at any rates lower then by the aforeſaid apprizements they are valued at, and ſo as the money for which they ſhall be ſo ſold, be paid with all poſſible expedition in to the ſame Treaſury hereafter mentioned, for the uſe hereafter appointed: And the ſaid Contractors, or any three or more of them, ſhall be, and are hereby authorized to chuſe and ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>point a Clerk-Regiſter, and ſuch other Officers or Agents as they ſhall think fit and finde need<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful,
<pb n="343" facs="tcp:169034:7"/> for the better diſcharge of the truſt, and diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>patch of the ſervice hereby committed to them; and for their own, and their Agents and Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers pains and charges therein, ſhall have five pence in the pound allowed them out of all ſuch moneys as ſhall be made by ſale of the ſaid goods and premiſes, and out of the moneys to be raiſed, levied and received for and as the forfeiture of any buyer or buyers, making default as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid in <hi>non</hi> performance of his or their bargain; which allowance of five pence <hi>per</hi> pound, ſhall be paid by the Treaſurer hereafter mentioned un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to the ſaid Contractors, or to whom they or any three or more of them ſhall from time to time ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>point to receive the ſame for their uſe, by warrant under their hands &amp; ſeals to the ſaid Treaſurers directed; out of which allowance they are to ſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tisfie all and every the Agents and Officers by them to be imployed in this Service; and to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fray all other charges of the ſame (except for Tranſportation and Sale of ſuch particulars as ſhall be ſent into any Forreign parts as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, to be there ſold) the charges whereof ſhall be allowed and ſatisfied out of the improvement of the price of ſuch particulars above what they would yield, if ſold here. And it is further En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>acted by the authority aforeſaid, That <hi>Humphrey Jones,</hi> and <hi>John Hunt,</hi> Gentlemen and Citizens of <hi>London,</hi> ſhall be and are hereby conſtituted and appointed Treaſurers for all and every ſuch ſum and ſums of money as ſhall or may be made, raiſed, levied and paid, by vertue of this Act, or any thing therein contained; and ſhall re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive and ſafe keep all ſuch moneys, and iſſue out the ſame for ſuch uſes, by ſuch warrant, and ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to ſuch directions as are in this Act ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed or preſcribed, or ſhall further by authority
<pb n="344" facs="tcp:169034:8"/> of Parliament be preſcribed and appointed, and not otherwiſe; and of all the moneys ſo received and iſſued out ſhall keep, and when there unto re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quired by authority of Parliament, ſhall render a juſt and true accompt, and faithfully obſerve and perform all ſuch things as by this preſent Act, or any thing therein contained; and accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to the true intent and meaning thereof, the Treaſurers of the moneys aforeſaid, ought to do, obſerve and perform, and for their pains and charges therein, and ſatisfaction of ſuch Clerks or other agent and aſſiſtants as they ſhall finde needful to employ therein, ſhall receive and have the allowance of two pence in the pound, out of all and ſingular the moneys to be received and accounted for by them as aforeſaid, which al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowance it ſhall be lawful for them out of the ſaid moneys from time to time to detain and keep, and the ſame ſhall be allowed upon ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>count: And although moſt of the Goods and Premiſes, having been of old belonging to the Crown, and not to the perſons of King, Queen or Prince, and now belonging to this Common<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wealth, the proceed upon the ſale of them might juſtly be diſpoſed of for publique uſes, yet conſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dering the many debts owing from the perſons of the ſaid King and Queen, and from their ſaid Son, contracted before the late Wars, and due unto divers perſons that are not Delin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quents, but have conſtantly adhered to the Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament, and ſuffered for the ſame, and many of them ſo neceſſitous, as that their condition can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not bear the want of their ſaid debts, The Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament hath thought fit, and do hereby Ordain, That the moneys to be raiſed by ſale of the ſaid goods and premiſes, ſhall be imployed and diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſed for and towards the ſatisfaction of the
<pb n="345" facs="tcp:169034:8"/> debts aforementioned, and of ſuch of them eſpecially as were contracted for neceſſary houſhold expences; which debts ſhall be paid out of the moneys to be raiſed as aforeſaid, as far as the ſame will go, in ſuch maner, and by ſuch proportion, as by authority of Parliament ſhall be hereafter directed. Provided always, That the ſum of Thirty thouſand pounds out of the firſt moneys to be raiſed by ſuch ſale as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, ſhall by the Treaſurers aforementioned be iſſued and lent unto the Treaſurer of the Navy, for ſupply of the preſent uſes of the Navy; and the ſaid Truſtees, or three or more of them, ſhall direct their warrant or warrants for that pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſe, unto the Treaſurers aforenamed; which ſaid ſum of Thirty thouſand pounds, ſhall be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the ſecond day of <hi>May,</hi> One thouſand ſix hundred and fifty, be reſtored and reimburſed by the Treaſurer of the Navy, out of his receipts for the Navy, into the hands of the Treaſurers named in this Act, for the uſes therein declared. And for the better diſcovery and aſcertaining of the ſum, and ſeveral conditions of thoſe debts, for ſatisfaction whereof the ſaid moneys are deſigned as aforeſaid, Be it further Enacted by the authority aforeſaid, That the ſaid Truſtees, or any four or more of them, ſhall be, and are hereby authorized and required to receive ſuch Informations and Accompts concerning the debts aforementioned, as ſhal be tendred to them, or any perſons concerned (whom they ſhall or may examine upon oath, touching the truth and condition of the ſame) and alſo by warrant un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der their hands, to call before them any ſuch per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon or perſons, who have any books of Accompts or writings, or can give any further Informa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion or Evidence concerning the ſame, and them
<pb n="346" facs="tcp:169034:9"/> to examine upon oath touching the truth, nature and ground of any the debts ſo informed of; and whether the ſame, or any part thereof hath been paid, and what remains due; as alſo to examine concerning the conditions of the creditors, &amp; time of the debts contracted, &amp; for what the ſame were reſpectively; and upon ſuch examination, to make &amp; certifie to the <hi>Parliament</hi> or y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> Councel of State, a true liſt &amp; accompt, or ſeveral liſts and accompts of all ſuch of the ſaid debts as they ſhal finde to be of the condition aforementioned, expreſsing the ſeveral ſums appearing due, and for what and when Contracted, and whether the perſons to whom the ſame become due by aſſignment or o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>therwiſe, appear to be Delinquents or friends to the Parliament; and whether they have lent or advanced any Money, Plate, horſe, Arms or furniture upon the Parliaments Propoſitions, before the 24<hi>
                  <hi rend="sup">th</hi>
               </hi> day of <hi>March, 1642.</hi> and whether they have conſtantly adhered to the Parliament, or ſuffered for the ſame; and whether their condition be neceſſitous, ſo as they cannot bear the want of their ſaid debts; and of ſuch debts, and to ſuch per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, the ſaid Truſtees are ſpecially to make a diſtinct liſt and certificate, as they ſhall finde to have been Contracted for wages or ſallaries to Servants, or for other neceſſary proviſions of Chamber, houſhold or Stables, to the end it may thereupon the better be determined, which of the ſaid debts ſhall be paid, in what order, and by what proportions; whereupon the Parliament will determine and take order for the payment of ſuch of the ſaid debts as ſhall appear moſt juſt and equal, as far as the proceed of the ſaid goods will extend.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="license">
            <opener>
               <dateline>
                  <date>Viceſimo ſexto Julii, 1649.</date>
               </dateline>
            </opener>
            <p>ORdered by the Commons aſſembled in Parliament, That this Act be forthwith Printed and Publiſhed.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>Hen: Scobell, Cleric. Parliamenti.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
